Guide to the Weinstein Spanish American war collection, 1898-1909
Department of Special Collections
Weinstein Spanish American war collection,
1898-1909
Special Collections M0277
Weinstein
ca. 2 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Scope and Content
Books, clippings, reports, articles, and pamphlets relating to the Spanish American war.
Container List
- I. 1. The Soldiers' Pocket Companion. by N. Hershler, Washington, D.C.: Chapman, 1899.No cover except fragment on back.
- 2. Prowling About the Pacific by David Perry, 1909
- 3. History of Our War with Spain by James Rankin Young in collaboration with J. Hampton Moore. Chicago: Monroe Book Co., 1898.
- 4. Program: Red Cross Transport Receiving Committee Benefit. Okland, April 20, 1899.
- 5. G.O. 28, War Department, July 20, 1916.re: examinations for lieutenantcies [U.S. Infantry in the Phillipines?]
- 6. Complete Roster of the Fourteenth Manila: Amigos Del Pais, 1898, Lt. Col. Charles F. Robe, Commanding.
- 7. San Francisco Call, Aug. 24, 1899.
- 8. San Francisco Chronicle, Aug. 26, 1899.
- 9. San Francisco Examiner, July 4, 1898.
- 10. San Francisco Call, n.d. California's Glory is her Victorious Returning Sons. (Special, illustrated section).
- 11. San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 24, 1899.
- 12. Military Notes on Cuba 1909, War Department, Washington, D.C., G.P.O. 1909(lacking spine).
- 13-15. The Campaign of Santiago de Cuba by Herbert H. Sargent. Chicago: A. C. McClurg & Co. 1907.
- 16. U.S. Navy Ships; USS Abarenda to USS Lancaster. Typed list (roster) with red pencil corrections.
- 17. U.S. Navy Ships; USS Maine to USS Yukon, Same description as No. 16.
- 18. U.S. Navy L to Z. See No. 16.
- 19. California Heavy Artillery; Batteries A-D. Typed roster with red pencil check marks.
- 20. First California Volunteer Infantry. Typed roster with red pencil checks and additions.
- 21. Sixth California Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 22. Seventh California Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 23. Eighth California Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 24. Alabama Volunteer Infantry, Arkansas Volunteer Infantry, Colorado Volunteer Ligth Artillery, Porto [sic] Rico Volunteer Infantry, First Territorial Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 25. Connecticut Volunteer Infantry - Georgia Light Artillery. See No. 20.
- 26. First Idaho Volunteer Infantry - 2nd Louisiana Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 27. 1st Illinois Volunteer Infantry - Illinois Volunteer Artillery, Battery A. See No. 20.
- 28. Iowa Colunteer Infantry 49th-52nd - Light Artillery Battery 6. See No. 20.
- 29. Kansas Volunteer Infantry 20th-21st. See No. 20.
- 30. Massachusetts Volunteer Infantry 2nd-9th - Heavy Artillery Battery K. See No. 20.
- 31. First Maine Volunteer Infantry - 35th Michigan Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 32. First Missouri Volunteer Infantry - Artillery Batter. See No. 20.
- 33. 1st Mississippi Volunteer Infantry - 3rd Nebraska Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 34. Minnesota Volunteer Infantry 12th-15th. See No. 20.
- 35. New York Volunteer Infantry..., Artillery... Cavalry. See No. 20.
- 36. First Nevada Volunteer Infantry - 3rd North Carolina Volunteer Infantry. See No. 20.
- 37. First Ohio Volunteer Infantry - Ohio Artillery Battery H. See No. 20.
- 38. First Pennsylvania Volunteer Infantry - Cavalry Governor's Troop. See No. 20.
- 40. 1st Wisconsin Volunteer Infantry - Wyoming Volunteer Artillery Battery C. See No. 20.
- 41. Indiana Volunteer Infantry - Artillery, Battery 28. See No. 20.
- 42. Utah Volunteer Artillery - West Virginia Volunteer Infantry, 2nd. See No. 20.
- 43. U.S. Infantry, 1st-5th. See No. 20.
- 44. U.S. Infantry, 6th-10th. See No. 20.
- 45. U.S. Infantry, 11th-15th. See No. 20.
- 46. U.S. Infantry, 16th-20th. See No. 20.
- 47. U.S. Infantry, 21st-25th. See No. 20.
- 48. U.S. Infantry, 26th-30th. See No. 20.
- 49. U.S. Volunteer Infantry, 1st-10th. See No. 20.
- 50. U.S. Volunteer Infantry, 26th-31st. See No. 20.
- 51. U.S. Volunteer Infantry, 32nd-37th. See No. 20.
- 52. U.S. Volunteer Infantry, 38th-43rd. See No. 20.
- 53. U.S. Volunteer Infantry, 44th-49th. See No. 20.
- 54. San Francisco Call, Sept. 22, 1899, clipping
- 55. A Daily History of the War [1899], clipping.
- 56. Oakland Call, Aug. 25, 1899.clipping re: return of the Sherman.
- 57. San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 24, 1899., clipping.
- 58. San Francisco Chronicle, Aug. 26, 1899., clipping.
- 59. San Francisco Chronicle, Sept. 17, 22, 1899., clippings.
- 60. San Francisco Chronicle, Aug. 20, 1900., clipping
- 61. San Francisco Examiner, May 11, 1900., clipping.
- 62. San Francisco Chronicle, May 24, 1901., clipping.
- 63. San Francisco Chronicle, May 31, 1902., clipping.
- 64. Leslies Monthly, 1898,re: Phillipines, 2 articles
- 65. San Francisco Examiner, April 19, 1898., clippings.
- 66. San Francisco Examiner, May 26, 1898., clipping.
- 67. San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 10, 1898., clipping.
- 68. San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 15, 1898., clipping.
- 69. San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 18, 1898., clipping.
- 70. San Francisco Examiner, Feb. 16, 1899., clipping.
- 71. San Francisco Examiner, Aug. 26, 1899., clipping.
- 72. San Francisco Call, Nov. 22, 1899., clipping.
- 73. Military Proclamation - Phillippines, Dec. 20, 1900.ptd.
- 74. Envelope of Pamphlets etc:
  N. D. (May 5), A.L.S. La Carolata Negras, Henry to Dear Mama, 16 pp.
  The Soldier's Letter, Vol. 1, No. 1, Nov. 1898, Ms. notes on cover.
  Souvenir Programme for the Grand Military Entertainment for Father McKinnon Monument Fund. 1/28/03.
  The Phillippine Expedition 1898. Pacific Mutual Insurance Company of California. Photo pamphlet.
  Photograph by Andrew P. Hill. Portrait of a soldier in uniform. unidentified [California Vol.].
  On the Pacific with Our Navy. Portland, Me.: L.H. Nelson Co. [1898] Illustrated pamphlet.
  Souvenir Program; Military Athletics, Presentation and Colors and Grand Ball, by First Regiment Infantry N.G.C.; In Commemoration of the Muster Out of the Regiment... Sept. 21, 1899. Sacramento, Owen H. Smith, 1905.